Too much context is always a problem.
Most of my skill MDs are built by my
agent, which means they're overly
verbose and I get way better performance
when I kind of cross-reference things.
So, whenever I think I have some large
concept that I is important, I'll say
put that in a new file, reference that
in the skill.md, and that improves a
lot.
>> There's three pieces here. You've got
the tooling, agents, and then you've got
the LLM under the covers. And I think
people probably think too much about the
model sometimes.
>> I'd always argue with people about
models and I'd be like, "This model's
better." And I would argue with people
about that, but but why?
>> The Reddit flames, the flame wars
>> on Reddit of this this model's better
and that was not better for me.
>> Even the trust me bro benchmark.
>> [laughter]
>> I don't trust them.
>> I like that trust me bro.
>> Tell us a little bit about what
CodeGuard is.
>> CodeGuard is really you can think of it
as security skills for your AI coding
agent, right? We use all kinds of tools
since it's got How do we ship that into
Wind Say or into Cursor or into Cloud
Code with low friction, right? That's
kind of the idea behind CodeGuard.
That's what we're we're trying to build.
>> The LLM or the agent will run those
scenarios in two manners. One with the
skill, one without the skill, just the
baseline we call it. CodeGuard did
really well. You could actually see I
think it was 1.79 times improvement on
the baseline. Were you shocked surprised
at that kind of number?
>> I definitely was. I was skeptical on do
I really need this? Well, we want to
give our agents all these tools, are
they secure, right? Are they
exfiltrating data? Stuff can be really
hard to observe when you have an agent
that's going crazy, right? You've
evolved beyond just traditional
software.
>> What advice would you give to our
listeners who if they wanted to create a
skill from scratch today,
how would you go about it if you were
doing that from scratch today?
>> It's really
>> Before we jump into this episode, I
wanted to let you know that this podcast
is for developers building with AI at
the core. So, whether that's exploring
the latest tools, the workflows, or the
best practices, this podcast's for you.
A really quick ask, 90% of people who
are listening to this haven't yet
subscribed. So, if this content has
helped you build smarter, hit that
subscribe button and maybe a like. All
right, back to the episode.
Hello and welcome to the AI Native Dev.
My name is Simon Maple and I'm at Cisco
Live today in Amsterdam and joining me
is John Gretzinger. How are you doing,
John?
>> Great, Simon. How are you?
>> I'm doing very well, thank you. And
today, in this episode, we're going to
be asking the big question. Can we guide
coding agents to write secure code out
the box? And can we encourage and teach
coding agents to be able to spot
vulnerabilities from existing code bases
or code changes? We're at Cisco Live
today in Amsterdam and we just did a
session just earlier on.
>> Yeah, your first Cisco Live here. How
does it feel?
>> Oh, it's it's really empowering. I
finally finally at Cisco Live session.
Tell us a little bit about what the what
the session was today.
>> Yeah, I mean, the session was kind of my
history as a developer trying to wrangle
this world of, you know, AI coding in
the enterprise space particularly cuz
it's, you know, challenging. to write
secure code. So, it's just kind of
walking people through my history in the
last 2 years to how these tools and
models have developed.
>> Awesome, awesome. And tell us a little
bit about who John is. You're a
principal engineer at Cisco.
You're part of the CX engineering team.
Tell us a little bit about what you do
day-to-day.
>> Yeah, my day-to-day is a lot of AI
focus, of course, but it's, you know,
kind of a newer team, you know, like 2
years old trying to figure out how we
bring more value to our customers with
AI, right? And it's building agents for
our customers, building platforms for
our customers, just really trying to
enable the Cisco technology cuz there's
a lot of it. Technology is complicated.
Can AI help us and help them? You know,
that's kind of what we're trying to do.
>> Awesome.
So, we mentioned Code Guard at the the
session today. I think there's a couple
more
sessions tomorrow and the day after with
Omar Santos.
And of course, Omar obviously one of the
proud owners of Code Guard. Tell us a
little bit about what Code Guard is
really there for
and the journey it's been on.
>> Yeah, I mean CodeGuard is really you can
think of it as security skills for your
AI coding agent, right? So, you know, we
we really want our developers at Cisco
across all of our orgs to use AI coding
cuz it accelerates software development,
right? We want to make more software,
but doing that securely and to our
standards is very important, right? And
so, our security and trust org is trying
to wrangle all that and figure out how
do we enable our developers without
shooting ourselves in the foot. And so,
CodeGuard was kind of a the first kind
of attempt at that. Uh internally, you
know, it's just kind of a list of skills
on what is secure development, what are
the kind of things we need to look for
while we're writing code, and then the
real problem was how do we ship that to
all our developers, right? We use all
kinds of tools at Cisco. It's a company
of acquisitions, so we don't all use the
same tool. Love to, but it's just not
the reality, you know, what I mean,
right? So, you know, how do we ship that
into WindRiver or into Cursor or into
Cloud Code with low friction, right? No,
we don't need to add more friction for
the engineers. So, how do we just make
that that easy? That's kind of the idea
behind CodeGuard. That's what we're
we're trying to build.
>> Awesome. Awesome. And I think it's yeah,
such a such an important problem because
people who use agents, they're stung by
a number of things, and one of them, of
course, is secure code.
And the biggest problem, of course, is
agents have learned LLMs, they've
learned on all of our bad habits, worst
practices,
and they average them out, and we they
we tend to get that back. So, it's
really really important to provide that
guidance that that that you know,
sharing that knowledge around that.
Let's talk a little bit about
We mentioned so many, you know,
developers at Cisco. Obviously, a huge
organization, huge enterprise.
How is a company like Cisco embracing AI
today across its development
organization?
>> Yeah, I mean, I from the can't speak for
our whole company, very massive, as you
mentioned, but, you know, I from what
I'm seeing, you know, I do do internal
trainings, I get some visibility across
our org on what what people are doing,
but there's pockets that I don't, but we
it's at the
to summarize, I mean, they our executive
leadership really enables this. Like
they want us to embrace this and learn
it, and we know it's a new technology,
so it's not all figured out, right?
There's no road map to follow for this.
So, they're they're creative or they let
us get creative and try new things, but
obviously, we have to do that securely
and without blowing the budgets, right?
So, I mean, it's a fine line to kind of
balance, but, you know, I I feel very
empowered as a developer in Cisco to
try these new tools and figure out
productive patterns, share that back
with, you know, my organization or
cross-organization sessions. That's kind
of the culture we have kind of green
here in Cisco.
>> Yeah, yeah, and and I guess, you know,
in the in the session that we had
earlier, we kind of talked about, I
think you you you talked about the stone
age and going forward and like the the
dawn of civilization where we are today.
And it's really like, you know, this
this progression of learning. What would
you say are the kind of the things which
almost like unlocked in your development
environment a new way of working? Were
there Were there Was it tools? Was it
practices? Was it, you know,
methodologies? What would you say are
the things?
>> Oh, yeah, definitely a combination, but
I think the tooling is is key because
early on, you know, it was just a chat
window, right? And there was only a few
models,
and people weren't really using them for
code quite yet. Like I was very much
heavily into live coding back then and
copying and pasting between, but it was
so clunky, and I was like, "There's got
to be a better way to share this. Like I
want this engineer to try this." And
that stuff took a long time to figure
out, and I think really with the Agent
IDEs, it's really when I started to see
that, "Oh, this is what I want. Like
this is magic." You know, I I make that
plan, that specification. I'm always
about that now. Uh
>> Curses, WinSurf, the curses, yeah.
>> Yeah, of course. Just specification
driven. Even your guys' tile is And it
now doesn't matter what
what IDE I use. That that tile helps a
lot. Uh
But yeah, that's just the tooling was I
think probably the biggest break through
the models, obviously.
>> Mhm.
>> But that's That's kind of a given. Like
we knew the models would kind of get
better at this stuff, but I think the
tooling
much better. Like if we take the tooling
we have today and we used it, you know,
2 years ago, it would probably still be
really good, right? Even with the older
models in there. So, like for me that
was the the difficult part to navigate.
It's like, how do I do this effectively?
Felt like I was getting burned a lot at
the fire.
>> Yeah.
>> like, "Ooh, shiny new tool."
>> Yeah, it's an interesting discussion
actually cuz of course there's three
things there's three pieces here. You've
got the tooling, you've got the agents,
and then you've got the LLM under the
covers. And of course, yes, there's a a
level of LLMs within the agents as well.
But it's interesting how sometimes we
just think of it as one experience.
Which I suppose it is, it's that one
workflow. But really there are a number
of there are a number of aspects here
that all contribute to a successful
developer workflow. And I think people
probably think too much about the model
sometimes. And I think you're right, if,
you know, with a good user experience
for a developer with the IDE or with the
terminal even and a good agent that
actually walks you through, that does
the planning, that does, you know, all
these different types of things. Those
kind of things, I don't know about you,
but for me were almost more important
than the model in some cases cuz it
allows you to perform that workflow.
Otherwise,
it's more of a bot if there's no
workflow. It's uh
>> Yeah.
>> It felt that way to me as well. Yeah,
like I I'd always argue with people
about models and I'd be like, "This
model's better." And so I would argue
with people about that, but but why?
>> Oh, the
>> Show me why.
>> The the Reddit flames the flame wars of
Reddit of this this model's better and
that was not better for me and blah blah
blah.
>> Even the the trust me, bro, benchmark.
>> Yeah.
>> No, I there's I don't trust that.
>> I like that trust me, bro. That's the
only type of benchmark I'm listening to
now. It's the trust me, bro. Okay, so
let's go into a little bit more about
Code Guard now. And we'll talk about, I
guess, how that evolved. When you
started, it was, I guess, you had a a
ton of best practices, a ton of
instructions or guidance. How did you go
about, you know, turning that into what
it is today?
>> Yeah, so I mean, the security and trust
org, you know, that's the Code Guard
kind of evolved internally and I think
they took a lot of like OWASP best
practices and industry standard stuff
that we already apply in Cisco
internally, but just kind of reducing
the context cuz if you've ever tried to
go look at OWASP rules, it's very
encompassing, right? And it's not
something you can even feed to an agent
that would make sense of that to make
sense to your code. So, it's just
simplifying it, right? Even for humans,
for agents, we need the same
simplification. So,
and then packaging it, right? So, they
wanted it to work everywhere.
It's just text, right? I mean, at the
end of the day, this is context we're
shipping.
They, um, you know, internally we work
on different methods to do that. I think
just a repository as code
is is a simple way that everyone can
understand, but then it's
uh, there's philosophical debates on do
I commit this to my repo, but then what
if it changes, right? That that
wrangling that world is still, you know,
not solved.
>> It's interesting what you say there
about, yeah, the fact that these are
similar old uh, similar the basically
OWASP rules, right? And and nothing's
changed in terms of the security space
and of what we're actually looking for
in code. Is there anything
agent-specific in there or is it
entirely just about the the produ- you
know, you could you run this against
human-written code as well?
>> Yeah, of course. I mean, it's mainly for
just traditional code, right? And AI
agents are creating traditional code,
but they do also uh, we uh, I think it
was 2 weeks ago or so, uh, they added
MCP security, right? So, uh, it's
obviously top of mind as well. We want
to give our agents all these tools. Are
they secure, right? Are they
exfiltrating data? Right?
>> Yeah.
>> That stuff kind of stuff can be really
hard to observe when you have an agent
that's just going crazy, right? So, uh,
there's also MCP security built in as
well. And I believe uh, skill security
is coming as well. Not into that. So,
it's it's uh, it's all beyond just
traditional software.
>> Yeah. And for the distribution of this
now, you obviously want all of your
users to consume the the rules, the
guidance.
Uh, and the way that you did that was
you built it into into skills, which you
made custom for each of the different
agents. So, there's a doc cursor rules,
there's a Claude skills and things like
that. Um, what were the kind of
problems, I guess, that that that caused
uh, when you were trying to satisfy so
many different uh, agents and their
different uh, their their different
structures?
>> Yeah, I mean I can really just speak as
me as a user of Code Guard and I
actually use all those toolings. So
>> I speak from the experience of trying to
install on each one. I mean
it's really just kind of a package. You
would unzip it and if you it's for
Windows if it unzips in that location
and that's I mean that's fine but again
maintaining that's very difficult cuz
some like I wish we would just
standardize on this stuff in terms of
like agents.md, right? But even some IDs
that claim they honor it they don't and
that that's really the problem and maybe
in
Windsurf with search to follow that
standard and then they don't do their
old rules. So now it's maintaining all
that context every developer having to
do that.
>> It just doesn't make sense. Like it's
just too much friction. People just
don't do it. And it just makes me not
want to use Code Guard because it's too
hard to
keep up to date, right? And that's not
you know, that's bad. Well, I want it to
be easy. It should just always be up to
date and just easy for my agent to to
pull in. That's what I want.
>> So let's talk about learnings then. So
obviously you created this. What were
the things that you took away from it
straight away from from using it and
playing with the structure of the of of
the Code Guard skill?
>> Yeah, I mean and it was so specific to
the
the tool that you're putting in of
course but you know, so I even I had to
go I learned stuff on how they deployed
it and like oh I was doing this wrong
when I was using this IDE, right? So
like that stuff was was great to have
like it's a learning experience but at
the end of the day it's really just a
bunch of like markdown files that are
intuitively titled for the security
practice that you're trying to do. Not
every security practice applies to every
piece of code or repository. So being
able to kind of pick and choose oh I'm
trying to do this. Yes,
session management's a big problem I
need in this in this repo
or SQL injection, right? Just take those
two skill files. I can read it as a
human and understand what it's what it's
doing but just feed it to the agent and
have it review my code and then you can
have a conversation about it with my
agent cuz I don't always agree with my
agent of course and sometimes it makes
you know, it's it's assumptions that are
wrong and I have to steer uh direction,
but with security it's I want that to be
easy. I don't no one knows everything
about the different ways you might
exfiltrate codes or
you know, exploit code. So,
>> Mhm. Yeah.
And what about like the repositories
that uh people who were trying to pull
Code Guard into their agents, how how
did it affect other people's
repositories?
>> Yeah, I mean there's a lot of opinions
there and that's that's kind of the
problem is, you know, some people say
this should be committed right to your
repository so it's always there, but if
you have a team of developers that use
all different tools, you're just
bloating your repository with all these
dot files for each IDE. Even I myself
wrote a script uh Claude wrote a script
that is like an agent slinker, so I
would write just one agents.md and then
I would run the script and it would
create all these directories and sim
link it up back to my single source of
truth.
>> Mhm.
>> Right? But it still bloats my repository
with
a mess, right? And so,
I I don't agree with the philosophy that
stuff like Code Guard should be
committed to your repo because every
time it updates you have to merge it in,
it it really complicates PR processes,
too. It's like just noise that your team
shouldn't have to deal with cuz it's not
part of the central code base.
>> Yeah.
>> I feel like a repository should really
reflect
what the repository is about and not
external stuff. Just like NPM packages,
I don't have the whole NPM package
committed, right? That would be crazy,
right? So, same concept. I really think
it should be treated that way as you
guys do. Think of it as a Tesla or a
Porsche.
>> Yeah, absolutely. And and now when we
think about the skill being used by the
agent, uh
identifying issues in existing code or
trying to find issues or trying to uh
write secure code with the guidelines as
the best practices.
Um
what were your what were your immediate
learnings from, you know, how it was
working and how did you know it was as
good as it could be?
>> Huh, well, I mean I didn't I think it
was a lot of why did you use the skill
this time? Why didn't you use it this
other time when I wanted it? And
sometimes I'd have to go out of my way
to be like, but did you even use these
these skills in in Code Guard for this?
And they'd be like, oh, no, I didn't do
that. Let me go do that. And then it
would change the code. It's like, ah,
he's wasted my time. Right. So, there's
definitely a lot of that with with any
skill development, not even just with
Code Guard. I go through that a lot.
>> Yep.
>> Um but but
>> Typical typical activation of skills and
with any agent, yeah.
>> not always easy. Like, what are the what
are the I mean, of course, you can try
to set up like hooks and stuff in cloud
code and make it hook off that kind of
stuff, but even that's not perfect and
it can be kind of it can actually be
worse.
>> Yeah.
>> So.
>> Do you have any tips or best practices
about how you can increase the
activation? Is it something that's in
the skill as a producer of the skill
that it's it's it's good to do or is it
something more as a as a user you want
to guide, you want to tell the agent, I
need you to do these things in this
order. What's the
>> Yeah, I mean, [sighs]
I use
when I build the skill, the the things
that are top of mind for me from what
I've just personally learned is keep the
skill lean. I think it's a best practice
anyway from the topic. But that's
something I've learned. Like, you can't
bloat your skill.md.
It's just going to become useless. So, I
think referencing things in the skill.md
is really the way to go. And when it
doesn't when the model doesn't pick up
on key things, like when I'm having a
conversation, actually, I just ask it. I
just say, why didn't you pick up this
hint in the skill.md about the security
review, right? And and then it'll
explain to me. I'll just ask it, can you
go update your agent.md or the skill.md
in a way that next time you go to use
this, you'll actually pick it up when
you do it. So, I tell the model to fix
itself because
>> It's a self-healing kind of flow, yeah.
>> Who better to ask than the model itself?
So, I that's my strategy and it works
quite well. And also, it's less thinking
for me.
>> Yeah.
>> It's like, why'd you do this? Oh, okay.
Well, don't do it that way and change it
for yourself.
>> Yeah, yeah.
>> Uh but yeah, it's a lazy approach, but
it works surprisingly well.
>> And how much can you you mentioned about
putting things into the agent.md and
things like that. With context like
this, obviously, there's a huge amount
of context and it's quite easy to blow
the context window pretty quickly. Did
you
Did you play much with the the context
window of how much you should put in,
how much is mandatory for it to read
versus
just allowing it to be referenced and
you can play with this whenever you feel
as an agent you you need more
information on this. Was there a balance
there?
>> I don't know what the balance is. I'm
still trying to find it myself.
>> We're all learning, right?
>> I certainly tried, but I don't know that
I have anything other than anecdotal,
you know,
>> Yeah.
>> memories.
And I don't have a lot of time to spend
engineering context management for my
age much as I want to. I got to write
actual code, right? I ship software, not
play with AI coding and, you know, baby
sit it, right? I really So, it's really
uh trial by error learning
um thing I don't have time to really
engineer, which is unfortunate because I
think that's really what's needed to get
optimal you know, the optimal
performance out of these is really
engineering the context and how it's
picked up, how different models key into
that, how the different tooling actually
is plugged in. It's a very complex, you
know, matrixy from that and I just don't
have the time to really uh dig into that
as much as I would like.
>> Yeah, yeah. So, what were your learnings
then once you had the Code God skill?
Um
what were the what were the
the lessons that you kind of like went
through in terms of getting that skill
as good as it can be?
>> Yeah, I mean, learning just the basics
of model activation and that stuff. I
mean,
not even just Code God, but I've written
a lot of other skills myself which are,
you know, I spend a lot of time trying
to understand like what works well and
what doesn't. Uh you know, too much
context is always a problem. You don't
want to blow up that skill that MD with
just unnecessary information.
Um I mean, most of my skill MDs are
built by my agent which means they're
overly verbose. So, I I I found that
problem very early. I think it makes way
more sense and I get way better
performance when I kind of
cross-reference things. So, whenever I
think I have some large concept that I
is important, I'll say put that in a new
file, reference that in the skill.md and
that that improves a lot, right? But, it
doesn't always pick up um on from the
skill.md to reference that when I
should. So, it's still learning how the
the best way to kind of do that on each
model is very different from that
perspective. So, it's it's not been
easy.
>> And and in terms of how you know the
context is is right
before you run evals, what we what we
was it anecdotal? Was it gut feel like
this is correct?
>> It was largely vibe feel, yeah.
>> Vibe feel. Oh, vibe feeling, yeah.
>> Yeah, so did I get a good vibe that this
worked well, you know, did it do the
task that I wanted to do efficiently,
right? Or did it stumble around forever
and you know, and 10 minutes thinking
whatever, right? So, no, it was very
anecdotal. Like I don't I still I'm
struggling to figure out the best way to
really
evaluate these models like software is
evaluated, right? And that it's not easy
to do.
So, so yeah, it's I don't have a good
data-backed way to
>> So, what did you Was there anything you
tried? Did you try using LLMs to judge
it or anything anything before the test
evals?
>> So, I'd say I I shared it with other
engineers. So, you know, only when it
was like, oh, I did it two times myself
and I I got a good result out of it then
maybe I would share with someone else
and get their anecdotal feedback, but
it's anecdotal anecdotal.
>> Anecdotal at scale.
>> Yeah, yeah. And then of course, they
would have they're like, oh, I use a
different tool and a different model,
right? And then they got way different
experience and then I don't have time to
go
>> Which could actually be nothing to do
with the skill. It could actually be the
agent, the model, and a number of other
things, yeah. So, so you we ran with
with test evals. We ran with the review
eval and then with the task eval. Um,
tell us a little bit about the the
journey you went on with the review
evals first.
>> Yeah, yeah, it was it was actually it
was fun. It was a good experience,
honestly. I didn't actually expect you
just ran
test scale review, right? And then
instantly within just like a couple
seconds, I don't think it was very long.
Um, but I always assume agents will look
away. So, I might have walked away, but
it was very quick. I came back and I
have this rubric to review, right? Not
just categorized feedback, but more
importantly to me, actionable feedback,
right? These models, when you ask them
for feedback on things, they tend to
just judge you harshly. And they never
provide suggestions. I mean, sometimes
they do, but they give you too many
options. But this is like grounded in
oh, well, this part here is wrong for
these reasons or you might be able to
improve with for certain things, right?
Um, I might not agree with those
categories, but for me it's an iterative
loop always, right? I want them all to
do as much as possible, but I still need
to be in the loop because I can't just
review, let it review itself and keep
going cuz that's a waste of money and
I'll probably end up getting something
worse in the end.
>> Yeah.
>> Um, so I make myself part of the review
process and I'll just kind of look at
that rubric and say, well, I don't agree
with this point. Um, but I really agree
with this point, so let's focus on that
one right now. Can you suggest some
changes for to improve that part of the
rubric? And then it would adjust it and
re-eval and then they get a better score
and it's like, oh, okay. We can start to
see the the feed the the improvement
working live and you understand it as
well cuz you're in the loop. So that's
how kind of how I do it. I really have
my model improve its own skills cuz at
the end of the day it's the one using
it.
>> That's what I'm saying. So you're
essentially managing your overseeing the
updates. You're you're recognizing and
and
having the time to agree
if you want to make that change. Then
the model does it, the model and then of
course Tesla, I the models in the
background. They they retest,
uh, provide the new feedback and then
you just loop through that until you get
to a stage where you're you're
comfortable.
>> Yeah.
>> Yeah, exactly.
>> How did that differ from, I guess, the
task evals? Uh, the task evals, for
those who didn't see it didn't hear the
the last couple of episodes, the task
evals are much much more real use case
uh, scenarios. So a number of scenarios
uh, that are based on, you know, what
the skill is likely to be used against.
And then the LLM or the agent will run
those uh, scenarios in two manners. One
with uh, the skill, one without the
skill, just the just the baseline, we'll
call it. Uh, and then you get different
uh, percentages. Hopefully with the
skill is a is a higher percentage
success rate based on the evaluation
criteria. Um, but uh,
Code Guard did really well in that. You
could actually see, I think it was 1.79
times improvement on on the baseline. So
we were shocked surprised at that kind
of number?
>> was for sure cuz I think anything with
the eyes was like use my contacts at all
improve your skill. It's like none of
that comes with
data other than the trusty benchmarks of
course, but
I think
I was skeptical on do I really need
this, right? Like I knew security I can
just tell it, you know, go read about
security and do this like where does
this help me? And it is optimized,
right? So, it's is this way faster and
the 1.8 improvement was impressive
especially when you have a baseline to
compare it to. Then you're know like oh
well, what is it actually better at? I
don't believe you. It's like oh, see
that? You can go try it yourself and you
see that.
>> And the joy is actually as well this is
kind of like very early stage with the
with the task e-bells, but the scenarios
are there to be reviewed and updated and
then sent back and re-evaluated. So, if
the e-bells aren't accurate or aren't
realistic, it's absolutely changeable so
that you know, the the the skills can be
tested against valid scenarios. Um
the baseline was 80 was 47% so, 47%
is the score from the evaluation
criteria
that a plain cloaked code did against
the the uh
the scenarios. 84% agent success so,
with the with the skill.
In some cases, I'm looking at scenario
five here where without context,
everything is red. Everything is x's on
the left hand side. With the context,
four out of the five turn into 100%
success. One
still 0%. What do you do with this data?
How would you turn this into actual
valid uh valid
turnaround for the for for for your
improvements.
>> Yeah, I mean it's a good I like the
scenario based especially because you
know, not everyone needs the same
security especially like the session
fixation one was especially interesting.
I think that's the scenario five
one because you know, having the using
the same session ID after you log in is
sometimes a bad bad practice. How long
does that ID live? There's different
schools of a on that. I mean us in San
Francisco, we're a very zero-trust
thing, so it's like that's very
short-lived. You need a new one at least
once a day. But, you know, for maybe
more consumer side stuff, it's annoying
to log in so frequently. So, maybe you
don't care about that. So, having a
different scenario for enterprise versus
like more consumer base and being able
to tell like is my agent aware of that?
Is the base model aware of that?
And is And if not, how can I have this
skill kind of give it that context? Cuz
again, perfect security doesn't exist,
but you know, there's different levels
you know, security will slow you down.
>> Yeah.
>> So, you don't want it to slow you down,
but you want it to be secure enough for
your application.
>> Yeah, absolutely. What would you say
with the with the biggest learnings from
the point of view of
how useful you found the eval data in
certain cases and what that what
learnings you then had from the
from Code Guard itself?
>> Yeah, I mean, it's definitely um
even some of the scenarios that it
helped create helped me I think, oh,
there are situations that I didn't think
about that it kind of applies. So,
really helped kind of
I don't want to come up with all the
scenarios. I might not be thinking of
them. So, it from that perspective it
was good to see. But, really the rubric
of how it thought about it and the way
that it explained it is like very
different than how I would approach it,
but it's a better way, right? It's more
scientific, right? Which I like and I
feel sometimes I'm just exploring
and I'm like I think this helps and I
don't know and I I really hate that
feeling that I'm wasting my time and I'm
not even making improvements. It's the
worst to me. So, I think it really
helped me keep on track and gives me a
hill to climb, right? Like that's what I
I try to do for all my evaluations for
my own agents is what are we trying to
build? What does good actually look
like? I think this gives you a example
of what good does look like or at least
an explanation of what good should look
like and then where you're missing the
mark. It makes it easy to just kind of
fill in the blank, climb that hill and
get to where you need to go. It it just
makes it less friction. Way less
friction to get there.
>> Yeah, yeah.
And using something like this with a
skill,
would you say
you know, for a greenfield projects
writing code from scratch, the skill was
maybe better for those types of
scenarios. Would you think brownfield,
where you have an existing
set of code whereby you actually want to
do more code review or or or slight
adjustments to the code? Where would you
say a skill like this actually has its
most effect?
>> Uh I mean, everywhere.
>> Yeah. It's a simple answer, but that's
the joy of this this type of skill
actually. It's like
>> is. It is. It is, but I would say I
don't want it to get in the way too much
for simple projects, right? There you
have some side projects I want to do and
I just want to code and I don't care
about security, right? If it's for me,
I'm the only one using it, and it
doesn't matter what the data is, sure,
I'm just having fun. Then I don't need
this, you know, but then it's like, oh,
I made something fun. I want to share
this. Now I got to go add this security
stuff to this, right? You know. When I'm
just having fun, maybe I don't I don't
use it, but for anything where I'm
actually going to share or ship, yeah, I
think it's absolutely has its place
always. Amazing.
>> So, what advice would you give to our
listeners who, if they wanted to create
a skill from scratch today, how would
you go about it if you were doing that
from scratch today?
>> Uh yeah, I mean, I know that I don't
have the best approach, but how I've
where I am today, uh probably different
in 3 months, but it's really building it
with the model together. I don't, you
know, write the skill.md myself.
Obviously, I don't have time for that,
but also asking the model
um what it thinks, right? In terms of
how do you think we should do this? And
I build it together, right? Not only
does it help me understand some of the
stuff I didn't, but it helps the model
understand what I'm doing, cuz
oftentimes I'll say we're going to go do
this task, right? And it makes a lot of
assumptions on what's involved in that
process. And that's wrong. So,
oftentimes, I don't make the skill
first. I'll basically tell it I want to
make a skill,
and then I'll say, "You're going to do a
dry run with me. We're going to do this
together, and then at the end, you're
going to review everything we just did,
and we're going to make a skill out of
that." And then we also have our first
evaluation from that as well, right?
It's a real-world scenario of me using
it to do what I want it to do. And
they're like then I tell the model to
build the skill off of that, and then I
adjust and improve from there. So,
that's kind of my approach right now. Um
I I It's very hands-off, but um
>> I really love that approach. So, it's
you're essentially
having the LLM while doing the stuff
observe
the interactions, I guess, because if
you say if it's if the agent is creating
something and you actually say, "Do you
know what? That's not how I want it
done. I want it done like this because
of blah." Then all of a sudden it
learns, "Ah, okay. My My My essentially
my basic route was to do this. You
didn't like that. As a result, I'm going
to start adding this as part of the
skill." Absolutely love that.
And also, if it's doing things the right
way and you actually don't comment on
it, it actually doesn't need to document
it. As long as it is deterministic
enough to do something similarish every
single time.
>> Right.
>> I I I love that. Um And then And then
evals and things like that, how would
you go about uh running evals? When
would you run evals, I guess, on that
kind of a uh
skill? How many iterations would you do
before you'd be happy with the skill
that you want to eval?
>> I'm definitely still all figuring that
one out, but I mean, I'm a big proponent
of evals, so I say eval always. But
obviously, don't have budget to eval on
every line change. So, it it kind of
depends, right? But I think
major refactors of the workflow where
I'm changing something in one scenario
that could affect another, I'm not sure,
you know, I'd run it. But again, it's
really use case specific. I don't have a
really general kinds of when I do that,
but I'd say it's kind of like a
if you're doing um semantic versioning,
right? It'd be like the the middle
version release, right? You want to do
it at the at the third release, you
know, that.
But again, it's cost and performance
balance.
>> A- And how about you kind of like you
mentioned obviously,
uh you know, a large organization such
as Cisco, you're going to have different
developers that are potentially working
in slightly different ways, but similar
policies, similar overall team ways of
working. But they're potentially using
different models and different uh
different agents as well. At what stage,
if you were building a skill, let's say
for a larger team,
would you do would you do it a similar
way, or at what stage would you try and
bring external thoughts in, because you
don't want it to necessarily be a
perfect skill for you, but then actually
not great for everyone else?
>> Yeah, I mean, again, it kind of depends.
I like to bring the users or consumers
in as early as possible, but that can
also be too many opinions too early, too
many chefs kind of problem, right? And
sometimes it works if someone just hacks
it out for a bit,
finds what works and what doesn't, and
then kind of
takes a first go at it and shares that
with others, and then you kind of build
from there. But it needs to be easy to
explain how you got to where you are,
and if people don't agree, they can try
something else, but too early might be
not good to have a lot of people, I'd
say.
It could be wasteful of time.
>> two loops. One one where it's like you
learning with the evals, kind of like
refining, refining, but there's no point
refining it too too much before you get
that more external loop of feedback with
the wider team, or even, I guess, you
know, extra
agents or extra LLMs to get that action.
>> Yeah, yeah. And that's one approach, the
other approach is just, you know, have
five people or five models all do it
asynchronously, and then we merge the
results.
>> Right. Just smash them together.
>> You know, if I'm in a hurry, maybe that.
But, you know, it it's again, it depends
on the skill.
>> Yeah, yeah.
Awesome. So, what what's next for Code
Guard then?
>> Yeah, so we actually donated it to the
Coalition for Secure AI, right? So, it's
kind of like a Linux Foundation, but for
AI's coding security stuff. So, yeah, we
want to share it with with the world. We
think we're Yeah, we found a lot of zero
days with it. It's obviously valuable.
We just want that to be easy for
everyone else to use.
>> And then, of course, it's on the Tessel
registry as well. We had a little play
with it just to just to be able to run
the the task evals and the review evals.
So, right now, it's at cisco/software
secure software-security.
It may not always live there, but but if
people wanted to take a look at it and
see what we did as as a first tile, it's
all there for people to have a play with
and uh of course if we if we move it
about or check the name changes, etc.
We'll let you know, but uh but yeah,
that was
>> Yeah. Yeah, people should give it a try.
Pull it down and just see if you can
find a vulnerability in your repository,
right? I mean, that's why not? Give it a
go.
>> Awesome.
John, it's been an absolute pleasure and
uh let's go and continue enjoying Cisco
Live, but uh thank you very much for for
the session that uh well, I say we gave,
but you gave like 90% of it, but that we
gave. Thank you.
>> Kick the can down
>> know what I'm doing.
>> I I can't believe it. I was heading it
in on the last on the line. Um thank you
very much for the session. Real pleasure
to be here with you and uh and thanks uh
for the session.
>> Yeah, thanks for having me.
>> Thanks everyone for for listening and
tune in next time.